Guide to the M. Perry Chapman papers, 1963-2010.
Chapman, M. Perry papers
- City Planning
  - Pocantico Hills, 1983 (Box 17)
    Transportation Study
  - Proposed Capital City of Alaska, Undated (Box 17)
    Summary
  - Reading, Massachusetts, 1975 (Box 17)
    Comprehensive Plan Studies
  - Rochester, New York, 1979 (Box 17)
    Downtown Cultural District Final Report
  - Rockefeller Property, 1983 (Box 17)
    Master plan and environmental impact statement
  - Rockefeller Property, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Town of Duxbury, 1981 (Box 17)
    Development Application design review
  - South Farm, Undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    Land Use Plan, correspondence
  - Kendale Gables, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    Note reads that it is relevant to Woolwich
  - Master Plan binder includes unlabeled CD, Undated; CD-2004 (Box 24)
  - Wisconsin Avenue Open Space Concept, Undated (Map-case Folder 1)
    Landscape Design Concept
- General Planning and Administrative Files
  - Comparing Campuses Map, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Sasaki Orange Book, 2009 (Box 12)
    Intersection and Convergence, signed by Dennis Pierprz for Perry Chapman
  - Current Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    Correspondence, memos - Mainly University of South Florida
  - Sasaki Associates - Financial Statements 1997-1996, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Articles, 2007-2008 (Box 20, Folder 17-20)
    Regarding Higher Education
  - Campus Maps, Undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Articles, 1997-2005 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Color copy of slides, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    Photo slides of various projects
  - Notes and newsletter, 2006-2010 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    Related to articles
  - Master Plan Design - Information, Undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Campus Planning and Design Studio, 2009 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Design articles, 2009 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Office Earnings by Principal, 2007-2008 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - World Congress On Land Policy, 1986 (Box 21)
    Program
  - Foundations of Campus Design, c. 2003 (Box 21)
    Insert dated 2003
  - Transforming Higher Education, 1995 (Box 21)
  - Cooperstown Central School Class of 1954, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Labor Detail report, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings of the Society for College and University Planning Mid-Atlantic Region Annual Conference, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    "Megatrends in Higher Education"
  - The Emerging Policy Triangle: Economic Development, Workforce Development, and Education, 2007 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Greater Scranton Roundtable, 2010 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Universities as Anchor Institutions
  - Source Articles, 2008-2010 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    For the Scranton Roundtable
  - Marketing Information, 2008-2009 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    Articles and reports
  - News clippings, 2006-2008 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Articles, Reports, Correspondence, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 21-22)
  - Universities and Cities Reaching Common Ground Conference, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Reports, 2004-2007 (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - The Campus of the Future: A Meeting of the Minds Conference, 2006 (Box 26)
    List of Attendees
  - University of New Mexico, 1992 (Box 26)
    Long Range Master Plan: Vision Workshop
  - Penn State, 1994 (Box 26)
    Campus Master Plan Workshop
  - Colorado U: Respect for a Robust Environment, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Article from the Architectural Forum
  - State University of New York, 1994 (Box 26)
    Campus Master Plan Update Guide
  - Articles, Reports, Correspondence and Notes, 2005-2009 (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - Time Sheets and Summaries, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Technical Resources, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Human Resources, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Planning Operations, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    Futures, Visions Statements, Staff Pieces
  - Planning Operations, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Principal's Goals and Accomplishments: Perry Chapman, 1992-1998 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Campus Planning, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    Background articles and information
  - Campus Planning, 1990-1994 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    Program and Statistical Information
  - Campus Planning, Undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
    Description of SA services; approach; typical schedules, etc.
  - Campus Planning, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
    Articles; Manuscripts and Abstracts
  - North Atlantic Society for College and University Planning; Town and Gown Conferences, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Society for College and University Planning, 1992-1995 (Box 26, Folder 19-22)
    Brochures and other conference material
  - Facility Evaluations, Undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Institutional Comparisons, 1988-1993 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Institutional Articles, 1985-1993 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Society for College and University Planning, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    Institutional Marketing Committee
  - SCUP and Missouri University, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Correspondence
  - "Planning for Higher Education", 2009 (Box 27)
    SCUP publication
  - Critical Issues in Facilities Management 7, 1990 (Box 27)
    Planning, Design and Construction
  - SCUP Newsbreif pieces on "Inspirations", 2008 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Articles by or about Perry Chapman, 1981-2009 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Planning for Higher Education, 1994, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    With articles by Perry Chapman
  - "Campus of the Future", 2006 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    SCUP presentation
  - U.S. Secretary of Education Commission on the Future of Higher Education, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Draft Report (For Discussion purposes only)
  - U.S. Secretary of Education Commission on the Future of Higher Education, c. 2005 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Issue papers
  - Handwritten Notecards, Undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
    Questions, possibly from presentations.
  - Papers and Talks based on American Places, 2004-2008 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - SCUP Founders Award Submission and Principle Review Forms, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Article for the Journal of Metropolitan Universities, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Material for SCUP article, 1999, 2005-2009 (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
  - SCUP Planning Award Submission, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Northwestern SE Campus
  - Northwestern Draft Plan Presentation, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Land Grant Article for Chronicle, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    Contains copies of 2 Issues of "Colleges of Agriculture at the Land Grant Universities: Public Service and Policy"
  - SCUP Journal book review of "The American College Town", 2009 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Papers Presented and Published, 2007-2008 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - American Places: In Search of the Twenty-first Century Campus, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 21-22)
    Authors final mark-up page proofs.
  - Talks/Presentations, c. 2007-2010 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - "From Multi-Centered Campus Toward an Integrated Campus", Undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - "Will the Humanities Save Us?, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - MP Article, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    Article about "Smart Growth" and the University of Missouri campus
  - MPC File, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    Contains material on the University of Iowa Campus
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 28-29)
    Final Text for Master Plan
    Suffered some water damage
  - Central Campus Material for ARC Domino Journalism, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - American Places: In Search of the Twenty-first Century Campus, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Performance Reviews for Perry Chapman, 2000-2009 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    Some water damage.
  - Perry Chapman Professional Profile Materials, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Handwritten Notes and Correspondence, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Memorial Booklet for Hideo Sasaki, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Memorial Booklet for Perry Chapman, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    2 copies.
  - Blank Stationary from the desk of Perry Chapman, Undated (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Box of Perry Chapman's business cards, Undated (Box 6)
- Media and Memorabilia
  - Plans - Digital Files
    - Lewis and Clark College, 1991; CD-2252 (Box 28)
    - Ohio State University, 1996-1997; CD-2253 (Box 28)
      Master Plan; West Campus
      AutoCAD Files
    - Ohio State University, 1996-1999; CD-2254 (Box 28)
      North Academy Core; District Plan South Campus; River Corridor District
      AutoCAD and Microstation files
    - University of Missouri, 2001; CD-2255 (Box 28)
      Residence Life Master Plan
    - Vanderbilt University, November 2001; CD-2261 (Box 28)
    - University of Missouri, December 2002; CD-2263 (Box 28)
      Consultant Procedures and Design Guidelines
      For Project #444001
    - Pickard and Sociology, Undated; CD-2256 (Box 28)
      Elevation and Sections
    - University of Missouri, Undated; CD-2257 (Box 28)
      Map of Vet School
    - Cornell University, Undated; CD-2258 (Box 28)
      East Campus Plan background information
    - Cornell University, Undated; CD-2259 (Box 28)
    - Southeast Gateway, Undated; CD-2299 (Box 28)
      Parking
    - Iowa State University, Undated; CD-2300 (Box 28)
      Ratio: Campus Master Plan Preferred Approach Study
    - University of Missouri, Undated; CD-2301 (Box 28)
      Southwest Area Housing Study
    - University of South Florida, Undated; CD-2302 (Box 28)
    - Parking Structure Site, Undated; CD-2303 (Box 28)
      X -Sections
    - Unlabelled, CD-2304-2306 (Box 28)
  - Publications and Presentations - Digital Files
    - SCUP Slides, October 2001; CD-2260 (Box 28)
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, Summer 2002; CD-2262 (Box 28)
      "Creating, Reshaping, and Preserving the Campus Fabric"
    - Harvard Campus Planning Course, January 2003; CD-2264 (Box 28)
      USF Show
    - Bowling Green State University, September 2003; CD-2265 (Box 28)
      Images and PowerPoint
    - Places in a Life, September 2003; CD-2266 (Box 28)
      Stockholder's Meeting
    - Learning Communities, November 2003; CD-2267 (Box 28)
      M. Perry Chapman and Robert Sabbatini
    - Learning Communities, 2003; CD-2268 (Box 28)
      Final
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, January 2004; CD-2269 (Box 28)
      Place Making; Corneil and Sabbatini
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 2004; CD-2270 (Box 28)
      M. Perry Chapman
    - WMAA; SCUP; Harvard, 2004; CD-2271 (Box 28)
      WMAA - Annual Meeting 2004; Elevate Creative Economy
      SCUP MA: Creativity Sparks Economy
      Harvard
      SCUP NA Tools and Techniques
    - SCUP, March 2005; CD-2272 (Box 28)
    - Northeast Mega region, August 2005; CD-2273 (Box 28)
      PowerPoint from Tyler
    - Campus Planning MPC Presentation, 2005; CD-2274 (Box 28)
    - The Campus of the Future: A Meeting of the Minds, July 2006; CD-2275 (Box 28)
      Sessions Proceedings
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, August 2006; CD-2276 (Box 28)
      Making Places II: Regenerating the Legacy of Place/Creating New Legacies
      Robert Sabbatini
    - Clemson, October 2006; CD-2277 (Box 28)
      PowerPoint
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 2006; CD-2278 (Box 28)
      Presentation, script, handouts
    - SCUP, 2006; CD-2279 (Box 28)
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 2006; CD-2280 (Box 28)
      Script and PowerPoint; Laura Shinn
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, July 2007; CD-2281 (Box 28)
      "Campus of the Future: New Paradigms in Campus Planning and Design"
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, July 2007; CD-2282-2283 (Box 28)
      PowerPoint Show #1 (2 copies)
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, July 2007; CD-2284-2285 (Box 28)
      PowerPoint Show #2 (2 copies)
    - Greening of the Campus Conference, September 2007; CD-2286 (Box 28)
      "Ethic of Place" Presentation
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 2007; CD-2287 (Box 28)
      Show
    - Mid-Atlantic SCUP, March 2008; CD-2288 (Box 28)
      Plenary Presentation
    - SCUP, July 2008; CD-2289 (Box 28)
      "Creating Global-Ready Places"
    - SCUP, July 2008; CD-2290 (Box 28)
      "Planning Inspirations: Past, Present: and Future - Founder's Award
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, August 2009; CD-2291 (Box 28)
      Planning and Building Sustainable Campuses
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design, August 2009; CD-2292 (Box 28)
      Planning and Building Sustainable Campuses. PowerPoint.
    - University of Missouri, 2010; CD-2293 (Box 28)
      M.P. Documentary
    - SCUP Conference, 2011; CD-2294 (Box 28)
      Note reads: Superseded
    - SCUP Conference, 2011; CD-2295 (Box 28)
    - University of Missouri, Undated; CD-2296 (Box 28)
    - FAICP submission, Undated; CD-2297 (Box 28)
    - Sasaki Sports, Undated; CD-2298 (Box 28)
      Interview PowerPoints
    - American Place: In Search of the Twenty-first-century Campus, August 2004; CD-2307 (Box 28)
      25% Draft
    - American Place: In Search of the Twenty-first-century Campus, October 2004; CD-2308 (Box 28)
      Work completed by October 30, 2004
    - American Place: In Search of the Twenty-first-century Campus, February 2005; CD-2309 (Box 28)
      60% Draft
    - University of Missouri, September 1998; V-7248 (Box 6)
      Master Planning, Assorted Slides and Missouri Forum
  - Memorabilia
    - Marquette University, Undated; MU-2266 (Map-case Folder 2)
      Flag/Banner
    - California State University Monterey Bay, Undated; MU-2267 (Map-case Folder 2)
      Pennant